嘿  你好吗？
Hey. How you doin' in there?
舒服地坐好了吗？都安顿好了？很好
You sitting comfortably? All settled in? Okay, good.
现在听好了
Now, listen.
我要给你讲一个故事
I'm gonna tell you a story.
一个我们从养鸡场逃跑的故事
It's all about the time we escaped from a chicken farm.
有一个农妇  看见了吗？
There was this farmer, see?
她很讨厌鸡
And she absolutely hated chickens.
把鸡像囚犯一样关起来
Kept them locked up like prisoners.
她可以说是一个居心叵测的刽子手
I guess you could say she had a real axe to grind.
引进了一台可以把鸡变成馅饼的机器
Got herself a machine that turned chickens into pies.
大家不要慌！
We mustn't panic!
但她没想到的是  鸡群中竟然有一位自由斗士
But what she didn't plan on was going toe to toe
敢于正面反抗她的迫害
with a certain freedom-fighting chick.
她勇猛无畏  一心一意只追求一样东西
She was fierce, fearless, and wanted one thing and one thing only.
自由
Freedom.
是她让我们团结起来
She pulled us all together…
是她给了我们飞翔的翅膀  让我们逃离地狱！
…and gave us the wings to fly right outta that hen-hole.
她不但救出了所有的鸡
She got every chicken out of there.
还解决了那个邪恶的农妇
And got rid of that wicked farmer to boot.
再见喽
Bye-bye.
养鸡场被毁  疑似家禽作祟
知道那位自由斗士是谁吗？
And you know who that freedom-fighting chicken was?
正是你的妈妈
Your very own mom.
洛奇  现在就讲睡前故事  有点为时过早了吧？
Rocky, don't you think bedtime stories might be a bit premature?
胎教很重要的  总得让孩子了解父母的过去嘛
Well… I mean, you're never too young to learn where you came from.
但谢天谢地  那些日子已经结束了
But those days are over, thank goodness.
我们赢得了幸福的结局
We've got our happy ending.
过上了美满的生活
We're living in it.
果子过去了哦  麦可
Your way, Mac.
又有水果来喽  邦蒂
More fruit coming, Bunty.
我可真谢谢你  麦可  踩得我都快渴死了
Oh! Oh, thanks, Mac, 'cause I'm working up a thirst here.
干得好  邦蒂  再接再厉
Good work, Bunty. Keep it up.
知道吗？
You know what?
我觉得现在是时候放下过去了
I think it's time to put the past behind us.
结果又织得很好呢  是呀  真可爱
Turned out nice again. -Ooh, yeah. Lovely.
过去？
Past?
什么过去？
What past?
那段过去  贴在后面墙上的那些
That past, behind us.
但这些是我们的光辉岁月呀
But these, these are our glory days.
这是我们的传奇
That's who we are.
这是我们的过往
It's who we were.
我们经历那些磨难  就是为了不让孩子受同样的苦
We went through all that so our baby doesn't have to.
好吧  你说得对
Y'know, you are right.
从现在起  我们唯一的任务就是保护宝宝的安全
From now on, our only mission is to keep our baby safe.
别担心  一切包在洛奇身上
Don't you worry. Ol' Rocky here is on the case.
我该怎么办？我该怎么办？
What do I do? What do I do?
它在跳！
Whoo-hoo! -It's hopping!
快抓住它！
Just grab it!
不好！
Oh no!
小心！有蛋飞过
Egg's up!
天哪  蛋活了
Good grief. A live shell.
大家快散开！
Clear the area!
-抓住它！
Whoo-hoo! Oh! Get it!
-小心！
Watch out! Huh?
不！
No!
看呀
Would you look at that.
我们有自己的小宝宝了
We've got ourselves a family.
噢  你看她多可爱  洛奇
Oh, look at her, Rocky.
她太完美了
She's perfect.
欢迎来到这个世界
Welcome to the world.
莫莉
Molly. Mm.
真是只漂亮的小母鸡
Ah, what a bonny wee hen.
瞧这双小腿  跟她爸爸的一样细长
Oh, she's got her father's spindly little legs.
你要加强锻炼哟  知道吧？
We need to build them up, what, what.
想当初我在皇家空军服役时  早餐前会先做50个深蹲
When I was in the RAF, we did 50 squats before breakfast.
如今没这体力了
That's gone.
-我给她做了一辆自行车  -真的吗？
-I made her a bicycle. -Really?
你织了一辆自行车
Oh. You knitted one.
真有创意
What a lovely… thought.
谢谢你  芭布丝
Thank you, Babs.
我想说  从今往后  我们的小岛乐园会变得更加欢乐
Y'know, I'd say our little island paradise just got a little more
“宛如天堂”
"paradisier."
咯咯咕咕哒！
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
小鸡快跑
逃出鸡块工厂
♪ Let me tell you all about my baby ♪
♪ You will never find her misbehavin' ♪
♪ Oh, she's such a diamond… ♪
莫莉！糟了！快拦住婴儿车！
Molly! No, no, no, no! Stop that pram!
♪ Everybody tells me she's a charmer ♪
♪ Never gets in trouble ♪
♪ She's the apple of my eye ♪
♪ She's so sweet… ♪ No!
不愧是我勇敢的小姑娘  好样的！
-That's my brave little girl. -Yes! You're doing great!
-不  -别上去！
-Ooh. No, no, no, no. -No, no, no!
莫莉  这有点勇敢过头了！
Molly, that's a bit too brave.
当心  宝贝  抓住两边
Careful up there, sweetheart. Hold on to the sides.
抓牢…
Hold on to it. Ah.
别跳！不！
-Whee! -Oh no! No, no, no!
♪ Cherry pie, buttercup ♪
太不像话了！
-Outrageous!
♪ Sugar, little honeybee ♪
♪ Never thought That I would love another… ♪
-谁想喝茶呀？  -好  来喝杯茶
-Anyone for tea? -Ooh, yeah. Cuppa tea.
♪ All the way up ♪
♪ Can't get enough, I know ♪
♪ Sometimes she drives me crazy ♪
♪ I never could get mad at my baby… ♪
嘿  小伙子们  欢迎回来
Hey, boys. Welcome back.
我们今天给你带来了  不少优质的旧货哟  洛奇兄弟
We have got some quality old junk for you today, Rocky, mate.
-给你  -莫莉  帮爸爸拿一下
-Here you go. -Molly, hold on to this for Daddy.
-好的  再见喽  -下个月见
-All right. Well, nice to see ya. -See you next month.
你好呀  小家伙！
-Hiya, hen. -Huh?
再见！
Mm, bye-bye.
♪ I know ♪
♪ One day, she'll have to go ♪
♪ And leave me behind… ♪
好吧
Mutt. -Ah.
♪ 'Cause she's so sweet ♪
不  你这是作弊！你作弊！
No, you cheater! Cheater!
回头见
See you later.
♪ To keep her to myself… ♪ Hmm? Hmm.
-你好！  -早上好
Hello! -Morning.
-嗨！早上好！  -早上好！
Hello! Morning! Morning!
-你好！  -早上好  孩子！
Hiya! Morning, pet!
♪ Without my sweet ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Cherry pie, buttercup ♪
♪ She's still got the world to see ♪
你好  妈妈
Hi, Mum.
你好  宝贝  嗨  爸爸！
-Oh. Hello, darling. -Hi, Dad!
尼克叔叔！费彻叔叔！
Uncle Nick! Uncle Fetcher!
她刚才叫我“叔叔”
She just called me "uncle."
淡定  兄弟  淡定
Steady, mate. Steady.
但我从来没有过自己的家人
But I've never had a family of me own.
我也是
Me neither.
妈妈  我在想一件事  我们可以去那儿吗？
Mum, I was thinking. Can we go over there?
去哪儿  亲爱的？
Where, love?
水的另一边
The other side of the water.
我们已经谈过这事了  莫莉
Oh, we've spoken about this, Molly.
水的那边什么也没有
There's nothing over there for us.
尼克和费彻叔叔带来的那些东西
What about stuff Uncle Nick and Fetch bring?
不就是从那边来的吗？
Isn't that for us?
嘿  在聊什么呢  金吉？
Hey. What's up, Ginge?
洛奇
Rocky.
莫莉说她想离开小岛
Molly's asking about going off the island.
哦  是嘛
Oh, right.
噢  是吗？
莫莉
Hey, Molly.
你想看看世界上最厉害的发明吗？
Do you wanna see the world's coolest invention?
好吧
Okay.
这是什么  爸爸？
What is it, Dad?
它能为你解决生活中的所有难题
Only the answer to all of life's problems.
爆米花
Popcorn.
这可真是世界上最美妙的东西了
Is that the best thing ever or what?
还真挺不错的  不错？
Mm! It is good. "Good"?
简直太好吃啦！
This is great!
女儿  在你眼前的就是最美好的生活
Life, my girl, doesn't get better than this.
妈妈  你看见什么了？没什么好担心的  莫莉
Mum, what is it? -It's nothing to worry about, Molly.
什么事也没有
Nothing at all.
好吧  反正这里迟早会有人类出现的
Well, it was only a matter of time before the humans showed up.
乐园鸡舍
人类好像要把他们送去某家养鸡场
It looks like they're taking them to some kind of chicken farm.
我好久没见过你这个表情了
I haven't seen that look in a long while.
你没办法纠正  这世上所有的错误  亲爱的
You can't right all the world's wrongs, duck.
通知大家  今晚开会
Meeting tonight. Spread the word.
又来了
Here we go again.
出什么事了  妈妈？
What's going on, Mum?
为什么我不能再去树上玩了？你们开会要说什么？
Why can't I go up my tree anymore? What's this meeting about?
没什么  莫莉
It's nothing, Molly.
就是…
It's, um, just…
今年那边来了一群大黄蜂
There's some quite big wasps up there this year.
真的吗？
Really?
况且  我需要有人  留在这儿照看你爸爸
Besides, I need someone to stay here and look after your dad.
别担心  我没事
Don't worry. I'm good.
好吧
Okay.
也许你不在的时候  他可以给我讲个故事呢
Maybe while you're out, he can tell me a story.
好主意
Good idea.
晚安  我勇敢的大姑娘
Good night, my big, brave girl.
晚安  金吉  祝你好运
Good night, Ginge. Good luck.
好了  莫莉宝贝  你想玩点什么？
Okay, Mollypod. What do you wanna do?
嗯  你给我讲个故事吧  关于这个的故事
Well, I thought you could tell me about… this.
那不是我
Uh, uh, uh, that… that is… not me.
好吧  这是我  但这已经是很久以前的事了
Okay. Yes, it's me. But it was a long time ago.
还有呢？
And?
还有
And,
其实
actually,
这是个很精彩的故事
it's a… it's a pretty good story.
人类想要的不光是我们的蛋
It's not just eggs they want from us.
金吉那个犀利的眼神又回来了
Ginger has that look about her.
我猜她想号召我们出头  为那些鸡打抱不平
I reckon she'll have us charging right into the fray.
我不想要什么出头
I don't want to charge into any frays.
我害怕线头！
I… I'm fray-phobic.
-好了  各位！请安静！  -她要开始了
All right, everyone! Please, quiet! Wait. She's starting.
-安静  -闭嘴
Quiet! Shut your beak.
现在  大家都知道人类修新路的事了
Now, we all know about the new road.
还有卡车把很多鸡  运到一个看似养鸡场的地方
And the trucks taking chickens to what looks like some kind of farm.
养鸡场？
A farm?
别慌  没事的  贝瑞尔  听我说
No, it's all right, Beryl. Listen. Listen.
根据以往的经验  我们都明白这一切意味着什么
We know from experience what that can mean.
我们不能视而不见
It's something we just can't ignore.
我们只有一个选择
We really only have one choice.
我不想听
I don't want to hear it.
我们必须采取行动
We've got to do something.
我们得隐藏起来
We have to hide.
隐藏？
Hide?
对  藏起来！
Yes. Hide!
你是说  假装我们不在这里？
You mean, pretend we're not here?
没错
Exactly.
低调行动  好极了
Operation Lie Low. Jolly good.
我喜欢地雕  尤其是有条纹图案的那种
Ooh! I like lilos. Especially the stripy ones.
她的决定是对的
She's right, you know.
我们真没必要多管闲事
It's really not our problem. Oh, you!
你还好吗  亲爱的？
Are you all right, hen?
逃避危险不像你的风格
It's not like you to shy away from danger.
我知道  但我如今得为莫莉打算
I know, but I have Molly to think about now.
而且我…
And I…
我们不能拿来之不易的自由冒险
We can't risk our freedom
插手外界的事  毕竟在人类的世界里  我们都是…
by venturing into a world that finds chickens so…
美味佳肴
delicious.
拉起来
Lift!
很好！
Right.
现在我们只要保持安静  别引人注意就好
All we have to do now is keep quiet and not draw attention to ourselves.
咯咯咕咕哒！
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
洛奇！
Rocky!
考虑到目前的新状况  你还是别再打鸣了比较好
Um, given our new situation, maybe you shouldn't crow anymore.
不打鸣了？
Don't crow?
但这是我的爱好呀
What? But that's, like, my thing.
那你就找个其他爱好
Maybe you could do a different thing.
安静点的爱好？
A quieter one?
哇  看这个
Wow! Look at this!
莫莉！别靠近那里
Molly! Get away from that.
金吉  我们能不能谈谈…  她是对的  知道吗？
Ginge, can we talk about the whole… She's right, you know.
吱哇乱叫会害鸡丧命
Careless squawks cost lives.
我们得保持低调
We have to lie low.
我中午会讲授一堂伪装课
I'm running a camouflage lesson at noon.
如果你能找到我的话
If you can find me.
妈妈  这张树叶网是干什么用的？
What's it for, Mum?
那是什么？
Oh! What is that?
画上有一只鸡坐在木桶里
It's got a chicken sitting in a bucket on it.
还做着这个手势
It's doing this.
真好笑
Oh, that's so funny.
我们回家吧
Uh, let's go home.
他们要去哪儿？我们能一起去吗？
Where are they going? Can we go with them?
-看起来很好玩的样子  -对不起  莫莉
-It looks like a lot of fun. -I'm sorry, Molly.
-你现在还不能离开小岛  -可是我…
-You're not ready to go off the island. -But I…
洛奇？来帮帮忙好吗？
Uh, Rocky? Little help?
也许我可以在周末打鸣  你说呢？
Maybe I could crow on weekends. Y'know?
为什么不行？
Why am I not ready?
我已经是勇敢的大姑娘了
I'm a big, brave girl.
你总是这么说的  我知道
-You always say so. -I know.
但你还是个孩子
But you're still a child.
谁说的？
Says who?
我和你爸爸说的
Says me and your dad.
对吧  洛奇？
Right, Rocky?
对  没错  是的  听妈妈的话  孩子
Yeah, that's right. That's right. Yes. Listen to your mom, kiddo.
要不我打鸣只打一半？  只叫“咯咯”或者“咕咕哒”？
Oh! Oh. How about just half a crow? Like a "cock-a" or "doodle-doo"?
简短一点
Something that's a little shorter.
好吧  那我自己去看那些卡车好了  因为我是一只独行走地鸡
Well, I'm going over to see those trucks because I am a Lone Free Ranger.
就跟爸爸以前一样
Like Dad was.
我看过他的海报
I've seen his poster.
他以前就住在水的那一边  你也是
He used to live over there, and you did too.
我说过那话吗？我不记得了
Did I say that? I don't… I don't remember.
够了
That's it.
莫莉  你不能离开这座岛
Molly, you are not leaving this island.
你不能命令我留下  你不能替我做主
You can't make me stay here. You're not the boss of me.
其实我能
Actually, I am.
听着  莫莉  这里有你想要的一切
Look, Molly, you've got everything you want right here.
除了一样东西
Except for one thing.
什么东西？
And what's that?
自由
Freedom.
知道吗？她真的很像你
You know, she is a lot like you.
你的女儿一定很美味！
Your daughter is going to be delicious!
别劈脸！别劈脸！
Not the face! Not the face!
莫莉？
Huh? Molly?
-莫莉？  -莫莉？
Molly?
-快出来  莫莉！  -莫莉！
Come out, Molly! Molly!
-莫莉？  -莫莉？
Molly? Molly?
-莫莉！  -莫莉！
Molly! Molly!
-莫莉！  -莫莉？
Molly? -Molly!
出来吧  莫莉
Come out, Molly.
不！
No!
她离开了小岛
She's left the island.
这里也没那么糟嘛
This isn't so bad.
真不知道妈妈在担心什么
Don't know what Mum was worried about.
我长大了  我很勇敢
I'm big and I'm brave.
对  当然啦
Yeah, course I am.
我长大了
I'm big…
而且
And…
不是很勇敢
…not very brave.
你在干什么？你想找死吗？
What were you doin'? Have you got a death wish?
不想
No.
等一下  什么是“找死”？
Wait, what's a death wish?
你怎么这么晚了  还跑出来呀  小姑娘？
Isn't it a bit late for you to be out, baby girl?
我不是小姑娘
I'm not a baby girl.
我是个勇敢的大姑娘了
I'm a… I'm a big, brave girl.
你不也这么晚了还跑出来吗？
And isn't it a bit late for you to be out too?
好吧  我喜欢你
Okay, I like it.
以牙还牙  是吧？
Give as good as you get, eh?
好吧  我叫芙瑞祖
Well, I'm Frizzle.
你叫什么？
And you are?
莫莉
Molly.
不过这名字有点傻乎乎的
Although, it's kind of a goofy name.
我正考虑把它改成…
So I'm thinking of changing it to…
安静  孩子
Zip it, kidda.
车要停下  我们的机会来了
It's stoppin'. Now's our chance.
你要不要一起去？去哪儿？
-Are you comin' or not? -Coming where?
去跳上小鸡乐园卡车呀
To the happy chicken truck.
你也看见了？
You've seen them too?
对
Right.
那辆卡车要开去的地方
Wherever that truck's goin',
肯定是一个超酷的世外桃源
it's gonna be cooler than a penguin's toenails.
什么是世外？
Uh, what's a toenail?
什么是桃源？
What's a penguin?
看来你还有好多东西要学呢  快来吧
Oh! You have got so much to learn. Come on.
等等我
Wait for me!
她发现了我的海报  我就给她讲了一个故事
I mean, so she found my poster, and I told her a story.
那没什么大不了的吧
I don't think that's such a big deal.
不  那正好  鼓励了我们的女儿去做一个
Oh no. It was perfectly sensible to encourage our daughter
独行走地鸡
to be a Lone Free Ranger.
按照你的养育方式  她永远都是温室里的花朵
You know, if you had it your way, she'd still be in her shell.
那也好过在外面的大马路上瞎晃
Well, better in her shell than out on the open road.
那么  你也是生活在岛上的吗？
So, do you live on an island too?
不  我之前被关在  一个无聊的旧养鸡场
Nah. I was stuck on a boring old farm.
然后那些卡车出现了  但他们说我太小了  不能去
Then the trucks came, and they said I was too small to go.
但那阻止不了我
But that's not gonna stop me.
在那里  我可以坐在木桶里
You get to sit in a bucket.
有哪只鸡不想拥有自己的木桶呀？
What chicken doesn't want their own bucket?
我想要木桶
I want a bucket.
我们就是要这样  莫莉
The thing about us, Mol,
想去哪儿就去哪儿  想什么时候去就什么时候去
is that we wanna go where we wanna go whenever we want.
对  谁也别想  命令我们什么能做什么不能做
Yeah. With nobody telling us what we can and can't do.
姐妹  以后我们就同甘共苦吧
Me and you, kidda. All the way.
我的天啊
Holy moly.
听见了吗？里面好像在开派对呢
Hear that? It's like a party in there.
那是什么？
What is that?
你从来没见过人类吗？
You've never seen a human before?
我以前住的养鸡场里就有人类
We had them back at the farm.
他们有点笨笨的
They're kinda stupid.
人类负责给我们喂食和做清洁  基本上就像服务生一样
They fed us and tidied up after us. They're basically like waitin' staff.
喂
Oi!
喂  你！
-Oi, you! -Huh?
你们两个怎么跑出来的？
How did you two get out here?
怎么样  莫莉？
What do you say, Molly? Uh…
要不要加入我的奇幻大冒险？
Do you want to come on the adventure of a lifetime or not?
-不！  -糟了！
Oh no! Oh no!
莫莉！
Molly!
金吉！
Ginger!
莫莉！
Molly!
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
木桶在哪儿？
Where are the buckets?
等我们到了那里  应该就会发放了
I bet they give 'em to us when we get there.
-我们快到了吗？  -莫莉！
-Are we nearly there yet? -Molly!
你好
Hello.
哎哟  我的蛋蛋！
There go the goujons!
-坚持住  法勒！  -你以为我在干什么？
-Hang on, Fowler! -What do you think I'm doing?
莫莉！
Molly!
乐园鸡舍  所有鸡的美好归宿
嘿  看起来也不算太糟啦
Well, hey. That doesn't look so bad.
噢  看起来糟透了
Oh, that looks so bad.
好了  停车
Right. Stop here.
我们检查一下
Let's have a look.
-好  没事了  -走吧
-Okay, all clear. -On your way.
高压危险
大家不要慌张
We mustn't panic.
-不  别慌！  -我不喜欢这里
-No. No panicking. -I don't like it.
此时不慌更待何时？敌人占了上风
It's a perfect time to panic. The enemy has the upper hand.
大家把头脑放冷静些！
We must keep our heads!
把头脑放哪儿？我在努力想办法
Where should we keep them? I'm trying to think here.
别慌张  不  我说了别慌！
No panicking. No. I said no panicking!
-金吉  你说怎么办？  -我说什么来着？
Ginger, what do you say? What did I say?
要我说  上一次  我们逃出了养鸡场
I say, last time, we broke out of a chicken farm.
这一次  我们要闯进去
Well, this time, we're breaking in.
-这里味道好奇怪  -跟我想象的不一样
It smells funny. This is not what I expected.
这里  挺酷的  对吧？
This is, uh… cool, isn't it?
就是这样  我的小可爱们
That's it, my lovelies.
下去吧
Come on down.
看起来不太妙
I don't fancy that.
快来
-Come on. -Huh?
这边走
Over here.
-哇  -哇
Wow.
我说了会带你体验奇幻大冒险的吧？
Did I promise you the adventure of a lifetime or what?
来吧  我们去玩
Come on. Let's play.
耶！
Yeah!
我们去泳池玩吧
Let's go in the pool.
大家听好了  我们一定能成功的
Listen, everyone. We can do this.
只要制定一个高明的计划就好
-We just need a really clever plan. -Ooh. Ooh.
好的  我有办法了
Okay. I've got this. I've got this.
我偷偷溜进去  把莫莉救出来
I'm gonna go in there, and I'm gonna bust Molly out.
那你具体打算怎么做呢？
And just how the bloomin' heck are you going to do that?
就是  那个  溜进去
Well, by, uh… uh, y'know, going in there
然后  救她出来呀
and then… busting her out.
这不叫计划
That's not a plan.
这只是阐述你的幻想
That's just saying what you wish would happen.
对  光有一腔热血和理想的大旗
Aye, and 12 herrings and a bagpipe
而不了解实际情况  说什么都是纸上谈兵
are just a pile of mince if you havnae kent the rules.
你这话听起来有点消极哦
You know, that sounded a little negative to me.
麦可说得对  我们需要先了解敌情
Mac's right. We need more details.
我们只有一次机会  所以必须确保
We only get one shot at this, so we need to make sure
每一步行动都经过深思熟虑
that every move we make is carefully thought through.
我们不能急着冲进去…
We can't just rush in and…
洛奇？
Uh, Rocky?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
有时候就得放手一搏呀  金吉
Sometimes you just gotta take a leap, Ginger.
-准备好了吗  法勒？  -好了
-You ready, Fowler? -Ready.
-发射  -洛奇
-Fire. -Rocky.
咯咯咕咕…
Cock-a-doodle…
哇  进展很顺利嘛
Ooh, that went well.
好吧  好消息是
Well, one good thing.
至少我们现在了解敌情了
At least now we've got the details.
对  我们需要支援
Right. We're gonna need some backup.
不行  那地方连只苍蝇都飞不进去
No way. That place is impenetrable.
对  你们也进不去
Yeah, and you can't get in neither.
这是不可能完成的任务
It's an impossible mission.
应该叫“不可能的任务”才对吧？
Uh, shouldn't it be the other way around?
别犯傻了  费彻
Don't be a 'nana, Fetch.
听着  虽然看似机会渺茫
I know it looks like a million-to-one shot,
但我们清楚那里的布局  麦可认为有办法溜进去
but we know the layout, and Mac thinks there's a way in.
这是乐园鸡舍
This is Fun Land Farm.
它比我想象的小好多呀
It's much smaller than I expected.
谢了  芭布丝
Uh, thanks, Babs.
在一个看不见的角落  有一扇小小的侧门
There's a wee side door in a blind spot.
只要略施小计就能把它打开
With a cheeky wee trick to open it.
所以  只剩下电网这个小问题
So, only the small matter of this electric fence.
以及人数众多的守卫
All these guards.
摄影机驱动的持枪鼹鼠
The camera-driven gun-toting moles.
还有激光制导的炸弹鸭子
And the laser-guided exploding ducks.
拜托了  请帮帮我们  洛奇在里面呀
Please. You've got to help us. Rocky's in there.
真可惜  我还挺喜欢他的
Ah, shame. I quite liked him.
莫莉也在里面
And so is Molly.
莫莉？我们的小侄女？
Molly? Our little niece?
冷静  兄弟
Steady, mate.
你要坚强
Stay strong.
不！
No!
-所以你们决定加入了？  -说吧  需要我们怎么做？
So you're in? Just tell us what you need.
为了小莫莉  要我们干什么都行
Anything for our little Molly!
我们一定会成功的
We can do this, everyone.
邦蒂  亲爱的  有了你的力量  我们可以移山填海
Bunty, with your strength, my love, we can move mountains.
麦可  你是我们的智多星
Mac, you're the brains.
芭布丝  你是我们的针织专鸡
Babs, you're our… wool specialist.
尼克和费彻
Nick and Fetch,
你们是峡谷这边最狡猾的两个小混蛋
you're the sneakiest little toerags this side of the Dales.
-你太客气了  -过奖了
You're too kind. Flatterer.
还有法勒  再加上你的智慧和机警…
And, Fowler, with your wisdom and vigilance…
法勒？
Fowler?
然后随着第二波轰炸机接近目标
Ooh. And then the second wave of bombers approach the target,
我闪亮登场了
and that's where I come in.
事实上  法勒  我们要给你想一个独特的外号
Actually, Fowler, we need to find something special for you.
好
Ah, right.
就叫策应师怎么样？
How about… getaway man?
策应师？
Getaway man, eh?
听起来很重要的样子
Hmm. Sounds important.
我喜欢
I like it.
好了  我们快去整装待发吧
Right. Let's gather what we need and hurry.
天知道莫莉在那里面有多水深火热呢
Who knows what horrors Molly is dealing with in there.
这里真好玩
Wow! -This place is fun!
这真是世界上最美妙的地方啦
It's the most amazin' place ever.
我妈妈还说我们住的地方是天堂呢
And my mum said that's where we live.
哦  是吗？
Yeah, right.
你们住的地方  道路是用棉花糖铺设的吗？
Are the streets paved with marshmallows where you live?
能在上面蹦蹦跳吗？
Can ya bounce on them?
不  那里全是小土路
No! They're paved with dirt.
你可以一整天躺着无所事事吗？
Can you lie around doin' nothin' all day?
其实  我爸爸可以
Actually, my dad can.
好吧  这里的每一只鸡都可以
Well, everyone can do that here.
哇
Wow.
虽然以前听说过  但我没想到世界上真有这东西
I've heard of this, but I never knew it actually existed.
好酷呀  这是什么？
Cool. What is it?
“吃到饱”自助餐机
All-you-can-eat buffet.
嘿！
Hey!
不愧是超酷的世外桃源
Cooler than a penguin's toenails.
对吧？
Right?
只不过  在家的时候  我有工作要做
It's just, back home, I had jobs to do.
我会帮麦可收割庄稼  帮邦蒂拔胡萝卜
I helped Mac with the harvester, helped Bunty pick carrots,
还有跟芭布丝一起做纺线
made yarn with Babs.
但在这里  我就只能玩
But here, it's just play.
除了玩还是玩
And then more play.
他们现在会不会很想我？
I wonder if they're missing me.
太棒了  不是吗？我们可以随心所欲地玩耍
It's great, innit? We're free to do whatever we want.
快来
Come on!
对不起
Sorry.
芙瑞祖！
Uh… Frizzle!
我感觉这地方有点怪怪的
There's actually something strange about this place.
我也觉得
I'll say.
你以前见过这样的东西吗？
Ever seen anything like this before?
不好  这是什么情况？
Oh no, what's this?
你不该跑到这后面来  让我看看你的编号…
You aren't supposed to be back there, number…
你没有编号
Hmm. You don't have a number?
我可不希望有鸡在这里惹事
We don't want chickens making any trouble here.
尤其是在今天
Especially not today.
弹射吸盘枪
好了  各位  我们上吧
Okay, everyone. It's go time.
没关系  我在来之前上过厕所了
It's all right. I went before we left.
搞什么…
What the… Huh?
错了  你这蠢货
No, you mug.
照片放反了
It's upside down.
对哦
Oh right.
快去！
Go! Go! Go!
喂？
Yup?
一切正常
All clear.
快走
Let's go.
完美降落  可以收伞了
Perfect landin'. Right on the button.
收伞？
Right on the button?
好嘞
Mm. Okay.
放我出去！
Let me out!
照相机
The camera!
我去拿
I've got it.
员工眼部图像  防伪识别
格伦  夜班  托尼
“策应师”  她说得好听
"Getaway man," she said.
这不就是让我  给两只耗子当出租车司机嘛
More like taxi driver for a couple of rats.
好了  教科书级别的着陆
There. Textbook landing.
稍息  士兵
At ease, soldier.
他们八成是觉得我老了  不够格参与这次行动
I reckon they think I'm too old for this caper.
觉得我是一只  容易分心、整天闲晃的老公鸡
Some rambling old rooster who's easily distracted.
哦  说到这个  其实还有一个很有趣的故事
Hm. Oh, actually, there's quite an amusing story about that.
有一次  我在外面闲晃…
One time, I was out rambling…
不  我是在做军事演习  然后…
Well, on maneuvers, and…
好的
All right.
我进来了
I'm inside.
快起开
Get off of me.
尼克  我不想吓唬你  但你的屁股刚才好像说话了
Nick, uh, I don't wanna worry you, but I think your bum just spoke.
是你们？你们怎么来了？
Guys? What are you doin' here?
-洛奇  -洛奇
Rocky!
我们是跟金吉一起来的  我们来救你了
We're with Ginger. Uh, we've come to rescue ya.
救我？
Rescue me?
不  我是来施救的
No, no. I'm doing the rescuing.
我不需要被救
I'm not being rescued.
我在营救莫莉
I am rescuing Molly.
那你进展如何了？
How's that going, then?
这个嘛
Well…
听着  我没有嫌弃你们的意思  但你们只会拖我的后腿
Look, don't take this the wrong way, but you guys are just gonna hold me back.
我喜欢单打独斗
I tend to work alone.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
对  我是独行走地鸡
Yeah, the Lone Free Ranger.
好吧？我就快找到莫莉了
Right? And I am close.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
我已经热血沸腾了  小伙子们
I'm gettin' warm, boys.
热得快烧起来了
Really warm, actually.
有人闻到烤鸡的味道了吗？
Can anyone smell roast chicken?
早说了你们会拖我后腿吧！
I said you'd hold me back!
真要命
Oh dear.
一切尽在计划中
We actually planned that.
是吗？
Did we?
好了  我得去找莫莉了
Okay. I've gotta go find Molly.
莫莉？
Molly?
淡定  小子  别激动
Hold it back, son. Hold it back.
你看他们
Look at them.
感觉他们都有点痴痴呆呆的
It's like they're all a bit… brainless. Ah.
我不喜欢这里
Erm. I don't think I like it here.
是啊  它不像海报上  描绘的那么有趣  对吧？
Yeah. It's not as much fun as it looked on the poster, is it?
嘿  芙瑞祖
Hey, Frizzle.
我们去调查  这地方究竟是怎么回事吧？
Maybe we should try and find out what's going on in this place.
听上去像是一场真正的大冒险呢
Now, that sounds like a real adventure.
来吧
Come on.
我们一起去调查
Let's investigate.
来吧  你这小淘气鬼
Come on, now, you naughty little thing.
我是你的大鸡朋友  我只是想让你开心而已
I'm just your big chicken friend who only wants you to be happy.
芙瑞祖！
Frizzle!
刚才那是什么？
What was that?
你好
Hello.
你是谁？
Who are you?
什么？
What?
是我呀  我是莫莉
It's me. Molly.
很高兴认识你
Happy to meet you.
芙瑞祖  这是什么？
Frizzle, what's this?
快来  芙瑞祖
Come on, Frizzle.
我们快走吧
We've got to go.
但我从来没这么开心过呢
But I've never been so happy.
不行
No.
我已经长大了
I'm big…
我很勇敢
…and I'm brave.
芙瑞祖
Frizzle.
听着  我先去查清楚这里是怎么回事
Listen. I'm going to find out what's going on here.
然后就回来找你
Then I will be back.
我保证
I promise.
弗莱博士  你的客人到了
Dr. Fry, your guest has arrived.
兰食洛特骑士
Sir Eat-a-Lot.
好的
Right.
表演时间到
It's showtime.
面包屑
兰食洛特骑士  欢迎光临
Ah, Sir Eat-a-Lot! Welcome.
王国的骑士大驾光临  我们真是蓬荜生辉
What an honor to have a knight of the realm with us.
其实“兰食洛特骑士”只是餐厅的名字
Actually, Sir Eat-a-Lot is just the name of the restaurant.
我的名字是…
My name is… Oh.
在乐园鸡舍
Here at Fun Land Farms,
我们会尽全力确保  所有的鸡都感受到家的温暖
we do everything we can to make our chickens feel right at home.
不得不说  我从来没见过  像这样的养鸡场  弗莱博士
Well, I must say, I've never seen a farm like this before, Dr. Fry.
真有必要把安保做得如此严密吗？
Is all this security really necessary?
是的
Oh yes.
莫莉
Molly.
我跟您说  这些大门背后的秘密
You see, behind these doors are secrets
将给整个家禽饲养技术界  带来天翻地覆的变化
that will change the world of poultry technology forever.
快来
Come on.
不！
No!
喂  你们在干什么？
Oi, what are you lot doing?
-进攻！  -进攻！
Attack!
这地方简直是个迷宫
This place is a maze.
我怎么可能找到莫莉嘛？
How am I ever gonna find Molly in here?
她在那儿
There she is. Huh?
莫莉？
Molly?
莫莉！
Molly! Molly!
餐厅的生意如何？
And, um, how's the restaurant business?
不太景气
Actually, a little slow.
好吧  我想我们应该能帮上忙
Oh well, I think we can help you with that.
莫莉！
Molly!
不！
No! No!
莫莉
Molly! Molly! Molly!
金吉？
Ah. Ginger?
好的  我上去了
Right. I'm gone.
我们就不能坐电梯吗？
Well, can't we just take the lift?
我只想说  弗莱博士  你最好别让我…
All I can say, Dr. Fry, is this had better be…
失望
good.
我的搭档很快就到
My, uh, partner will be joining us shortly.
我们录制了一个小小的介绍片  您可以边看边等
In the meantime, we've prepared a little presentation.
请坐
Please, be seated.
乐园鸡舍呈献
这是一只普通的鸡
This is an ordinary chicken.
平平无奇、反应迟钝、容易受惊
Plain, dull, and easily frightened.
正如所有头脑简单的生物一样
Like any simpleminded creature,
当面临屠宰流水线时  它的天性就是
its natural instincts, when faced with processing,
会感到恐惧和慌乱
is fear and panic.
这种情绪会导致肌肉紧张
When this occurs, the muscles tense,
令结缔组织产生结节
which cause the connective tissues to form knots.
结果呢？
The result?
鸡肉就变得又干又硬  丧失风味
Meat that is tough, dry, and flavorless.
妈妈  这个肉又干又硬  而且没有味道
Mummy, this meat is tough, dry, and flavorless.
我恨你  妈咪
-I hate you, Mummy. -Oh!
莫莉
Molly.
孩子不领情  别怕
Fear not, underappreciated mother.
如果科学能改变这一切呢？
For what if science could change all that?
如果科学能改变  鸡在面对恐惧时的反应呢？
For what if science could alter a chicken's response to fear?
如果科学  能让一只鸡快乐地被宰杀呢？
What if it could make a chicken happy to be processed?
那你一定会说：“好样的  科学”
Then you'd say, "Well done, science."
因为快乐的鸡
Because a happy chicken
就是美味的鸡
is a tasty chicken.
这真是世界上最好吃的鸡肉
This is the most delicious chicken in the whole wide world.
我爱你  妈咪
I love you, Mummy.
谢谢你  科学
Thank you, science.
乐园鸡舍
莫莉
Molly.
这部小短片的构思很巧妙  弗莱博士
That's a clever little cartoon, Dr. Fry.
但那真的能实现吗？
But will you be able to do it?
我们已经实现了
We already have.
这个声音
That voice.
请容我向您介绍我的妻子
Allow me to introduce my wife.
麦丽莎·特维迪
Melisha Tweedy.
欢迎来到未来
Welcome to the future.
是她
It's her.
亲爱的  这位是兰食洛特骑士
Darling, this is Sir Eat-a-Lot.
我叫雷金纳·史密斯
The name is Reginald Smith.
兰食洛特骑士  只是我家连锁餐厅的名字
Sir Eat-a-Lot is just the name of the restaurant chain.
你好  雷金纳
Hello, Reginald.
看来你已经见过  我的现任丈夫弗莱博士了
I see you've met my current husband, Dr. Fry.
我看上的是他继承的  丰厚遗产和大片土地吗？
Was I attracted to his large inheritance and vast acres of land?
不  我看上的是他的头脑
No, it was his mind.
表面上或许看不出来  但他其实是一个天才哦
You probably can't tell by looking at him, but he's a genius.
你过奖了  亲爱的
You flatter me, darling.
他有牛津大学和剑桥大学的多个学位  包括临床神经学
With degrees from Oxford and Cambridge in clinical neurology,
行为心理学、基因工程学
behavioral psychology, genetic engineering…
还有戏剧学！
And drama!
开胃菜环节结束
Now you've had the appetizer,
该上主菜了
time for the main course.
跟我来
Come.
莫莉  别过去  回来
Molly, no. Get back.
放开我！
Let me go!
好了  试试看能不能找到莫莉
Right. Try and find Molly.
哇  你们快看
Oh, look.
洛奇和那两只老鼠上电视了
Rocky and the rats are on telly.
看起来好惊险的样子呢
Looks like a real cliffhanger.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
瞧呀
Oh, look.
它们喜欢新加入的蛋蛋旋转杯
They like the new egg cup ride.
芙瑞祖
Frizzle.
妈妈？
Mum?
噢  我的莫莉宝贝
Oh, Mollypod.
-你没事吧？  -没事
-Are you okay? -Yes.
答应我  别再偷跑出来了
Promise never to run away again.
-他们有没有伤害你？  -我没事  但他们好像会吃…
-Did they hurt you? -I'm fine, but I think they eat…
好了  快干正事
Come on. Get on with it. -Shh.
好嘞  亲爱的
Right you are, pumpkin.
请看
Behold.
就是这个遥控器
The remote control.
还有另外两个遥控器
And the other remote controls.
为什么有三个遥控器？
Why three?
谁知道呢？
Nobody knows.
我来选一选
Let's go with…
就它了
that one.
-我为什么在打高尔夫？  -我在哪儿？
-Why am I playing golf? -Where am I?
-我在干什么？  -莫莉？你在哪儿  莫莉？
-What am I doing? -Molly? Where are you, Molly?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
不是  搞错了  亲爱的
No, no, no. Wrong one, my angel.
这是关机键
That's the off button.
让我来吧
Allow me.
是我
It's me.
她中奖了
She's won the prize.
哇哦
Oh wow.
好幸运的鸡呀！
What a lucky ducky!
不  别去
No. Stop.
快跑  小鸡！快跑呀！
Run, chicken! Run!
再见！
Bye!
祝你玩得开心！
Have a nice time!
看着我  不要移开视线
Look at me, and do not look away.
请看
Behold,
鸡块的新时代
the dawn of the nugget.
我爱你  妈咪
I love you, Mummy.
我是说  真好吃
Um… Um, I… I… I mean, it's delicious.
想象一下
Picture it.
在每一个城镇的每一条街道上
On every street, in every town.
人群川流不息
People on the go.
当代社会的摩登新人类
Modern people in a modern world.
他们想要食物  而且要快
They want their food, and they want it fast.
而我们能一桶接一桶地提供给他们
And we will give it to them by the bucketful.
快餐
Fast food.
我喜欢  这玩意或许有搞头
I like it. This could be big.
不！这是巨大的商机
No. It will be huge.
而且麦丽莎·特维迪也能报仇雪恨
And Melisha Tweedy will have her revenge.
报仇雪恨？
Revenge?
是收入可观  我刚才一时口误了
Revenue. That's what I meant.
明天一早我就派辆卡车来取第一批货
I'll send a truck to collect the first batch at dawn tomorrow.
我的鸡块和你的连锁餐厅
With my nuggets and your chain of restaurants,
简直就是天作之合
this is going to be a beautiful partnership.
我送您回车上吧  骑士大人？
Uh, shall I see you to your car, Your Sirness?
快走
Come on.
我们离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
不行  等等  我得带芙瑞祖一起走
No, wait. We can't go without Frizzle.
芙瑞祖？谁是芙瑞祖？
Frizzle? Who's Frizzle?
她是我的朋友  我不能抛下她
She's my friend. I can't just leave her.
我答应过会回去找她的
I promised I'd come back.
拜托  莫莉  你不明白
Please, Molly. You don't understand.
但刚才那些你都看见了  她会死的
But you saw what happens. She'll die.
如果现在不走  那我们也会死
And if we don't leave here now, then we will die too.
我不在乎  我不会丢下她不管
I don't care. I'm not leaving her here.
你只是个孩子
You are just a child,
你不知道正面对的是怎样的敌人
and you have no idea who you're dealing with.
再见喽
Bye-bye.
是你！
You!
回来！
Come back here!
可算逮住你了  该死的逃跑小能手
Well now, the little escape artist.
我不会让你坏我的事
You won't ruin this.
这次不会了
Not again.
马上回来  博士
Come back immediately, Doctor.
拿个项圈过来
And bring a collar.
养鸡场来了一位不速之客
We've an unexpected guest.
停下
Stop.
你把我们逼得太紧了  老兄
You're pushin' us too hard, cuz.
我好久没这么累过了
I ain't been this knackered
自从上次试用  那个仓鼠跑轮以后就没这么累过
since I took that hamster wheel for a test-drive.
-就是它  -你们听
Here she is. -Shh. Listen.
这只满腹牢骚的可悲母鸡
The miserable, malcontented chicken
逃离了特维迪的养鸡场
that escaped Tweedy's Farm
毁了我的人生
and ruined my life.
这到底是什么鬼地方？
What is this bloomin' place?
莫莉  你在哪儿？
Molly, where are you?
他把我的针织网兜撑坏了
Ooh! He's laddered me knitting.
快跑！
Run!
我给了你所有母鸡梦寐以求的一切
I gave you all a hen could want.
一个温暖的鸡窝
A warm hut,
应有尽有的食物
all the feed you could eat.
可你仍然不知满足
But you still weren't happy.
好吧  我现在就让你高兴高兴
Well, I'm gonna make ya happy now.
妈妈
Mum.
我得进去救她
I've gotta get in there.
我有个主意
Ah, I've got an idea.
-你是独行走地鸡  对吧？  -没错
-You're the Lone Free Ranger, right? -Yeah.
你以前经常被人  用大炮发射出去  对吧？
You used to get shot out of a cannon, right?
那是…你问这个做什么？
That is all… Why?
不管用  调高功率
It's not working. Turn up the power.
设备运行良好  亲爱的
The equipment's in good order, my love.
只是我从来没见过这么意志坚定的鸡
I've just never seen a chicken so strong-willed.
你还没见识到它真正的能耐呢
You don't know the half of it.
开到最大功率
Turn it up to full power.
最大功率？
Full power?
但我们还没测试过效果
But we've never tested it at that.
非得我凡事都自己动手吗？
Must I do everything myself?
丈夫和鸡都只会祸害我的人生
Husbands and chickens, the bane of my life.
你确定这样能行吗？
Sure you can make this work?
那必须的  只要是跟电有关的  就没有费彻不会的
Oh yeah. There is nothing Fetch don't know about electrics.
他还没学会走路的时候  就懂得咬断电线了
He could chew through wiring before he could walk.
-搞定  -好样的  小伙子们
-Ready. -Great work, boys.
我准备好起飞了
I'm ready to fly.
再见  老兄
Goodbye, cuz.
或者我该说  拜拜
Or should I say, "au revoir."
其实  说“永别”比较合适
It's more likely goodbye, to be honest.
我们走
Let's go.
快来  妈妈
Come on, Mum.
妈妈？妈妈是谁？
Mum? Who's Mum?
是你呀  我们得赶紧离开这儿
You are. And we have to get out of here.
为什么？我喜欢这里
Why? I love it here.
我好开心
I'm so happy.
不
No.
爸爸？
Dad?
莫莉
Molly.
看我的吧
Right.
它还挺会跳的嘛
He's got some moves.
妈妈  等一下
Mum, wait.
♪ 我们不会飞  我们是鸡！ ♪
♪ We can't fly, we are chickens! ♪
抓住它
Get him.
-你给我过来  -喂！
Come here, you. Oi!
抓住它
Hey! Get him.
全力搜捕那些鸡
Find those chickens!
♪ 我好开心！ ♪
♪ I'm H-A-P-P-Y! ♪
♪ 超级开心！ ♪
♪ 我知道我很开心！我当然开心啦！ ♪
♪ I know I am! I'm sure I am! ♪
♪ 我好开心呀！ ♪
♪ I'm H-A-P-P-Y! ♪
-来吧！  -小声点  妈妈  我们得保持安静
-Come on! -Shush, Mum. We have to be quiet.
但我想唱歌！
-But I want to sing! -Shh!
快跟我来  噢  好呀
Just follow me. -Oh, goody.
我们这是要去度假吗？
Are we going on holiday?
不是  我们得找到  芙瑞祖和爸爸  然后离开这儿
No, we have to find Frizzle and Dad and get out of here.
可是为什么呀？
But why?
因为我说的算
Because I say so.
你不能替我做主
Well, you're not the boss of me.
我能看见自己的脚
I can see my feet.
它们跑哪儿去了？
Where'd they go?
-快来  妈妈  -快点！
Come on, Mum. Come on!
-这边！  -你好呀！
This way! Cooee!
等等！
Wait up!
快跟上  再跑快点
Come on. Let's get a shimmy on.
金吉  谢天谢地  你逃出来了
Ginger. Oh, thank heavens you escaped.
真不敢相信  我们居然又碰上了那个可怕的女人
I can't believe we're back up against that horrible woman.
什么？特维迪太太人最好了
What? Mrs. Tweedy's the best.
-我爱她  -邦蒂
I love her. Bunty.
-麦可  是这个项圈害的  -她是最可爱的人
Mac. It's this collar. She's the loveliest.
-这个项圈害妈妈变得很奇怪  -最好的女人
It's making Mum act weird. The bestest.
-莫莉！  -莫莉！
Molly!
你好呀！
Ooh! -Cooee!
-搞定他了  -尼克叔叔？
-Ha. Got him. -Uncle Nick?
费彻叔叔
Uncle Fetch.
你们是怎么找到我们的？
How did you find us?
-就是从那个通风口掉下来…  -是爱  莫莉
-We just fell down the air vent. -Love, Molly.
爱给我们指明了方向
Love showed us the way.
上去喽
Going up.
-你好呀！  -金吉！
Cooee! Ginger!
妈妈！
Mum!
♪ 我好开心 ♪
♪ I'm H-A-P-P-Y ♪
♪ 我知道我很开心 ♪
♪ I know I am ♪
♪ -我当然开心啦 ♪  -我掰不动
♪ I'm sure I am ♪ -It won't budge.
♪ -我好开心 ♪  -芭布丝  你背包里有什么？
♪ I'm H-A-P-P-Y ♪ -Ooh. Babs, what's in your bag?
恐怕没什么能帮上忙的东西
Uh, not much, I'm afraid.
好极了
Magic.
要的就是这个
The very dab.
好痒
That tickles.
感觉好像我们  掉进了一个巨大的饼干罐里呀
It's like being inside a giant biscuit tin.
只不过罐子里没有饼干
But without any biscuits.
我的眼镜掉了
I've lost my specs.
我什么都看不清
I cannae see a sausage.
妈妈？
Mum?
妈妈！
Mum!
莫莉？
Molly?
你没事啦
You're okay.
噢  莫莉
Oh, Molly.
发生什么事了？我们这是在哪儿？
What happened? Where are we?
我不知道  但我们好像出不去了
Don't know, but there's no way out.
天无绝鸡之路
There's never no way out.
洛奇呢？
Where's Rocky?
我之前在那个大房间里见到他了
I saw him back in that big room.
是他救了我们
He saved us.
是吗？
He did?
加油  这次一定能行
Come on. We can do it this time.
我快坚持不住了
I can't hold this much longer.
费彻  快点！
Fetcher, quickly!
找个缝隙或者凸出来的地方抓住！
Find a ledge or a crack to grab hold of!
好嘞
Righto.
别抓我的屁股缝呀
Ooh! Not that crack.
面对现实吧  亲爱的
Face the facts, duck.
要想离开这里  除非奇迹出现
We need a miracle to get out of here.
嘿！下面有人吗？
Hey! Anyone down there?
-爸爸！  -洛奇！
Dad! Rocky!
别跟他说奇迹的事  免得他得意忘形了  我可受不了
Do not tell him he's our miracle. There'll be no living with him.
洛奇来救你们喽
Rocky is on the case.
-不！别跳！  -不！别跳！
No! Don't jump!
什么？你们说什么？
What? What's that?
我听不见！稍等  我这就下来！
I can't hear you! Wait. I'm comin' down!
别跳下来！
Don't jump!
来个合家欢拥抱！
Oh! Family hug!
我好想你们呀
Oh, I missed you guys.
好嘞  我们快离开这养鸡场回家吧
Okay. Well, let's blow this henhouse and head home.
那是出去的路  对吗？
That's the way out, isn't it?
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
莫莉  你怎么啦？
Molly, what's wrong?
都怪我连累了你们
This is all my fault.
我真该听你的话  乖乖照你说的做
I should have listened to you and done what I was told.
现在一切全乱套了
Now everything is a mess.
嘿  我那个勇敢的大姑娘哪儿去啦？
Hey, where's my big, brave girl?
那姑娘蠢透了
That girl's stupid.
你说得对
You were right.
如果我们还能回家  我一定乖乖待在岛上  再也不离开
If we ever get home, I'll just stay there and never leave. Ever.
嘿  别这样  莫莉
Hey, no. Molly.
这都怪我
This is my fault.
我不该跟你说什么  独行走地鸡的天方夜谭
I should not have told you all of that ridiculous Lone Free Ranger stuff.
不  是我的错
No, this is on me.
我以前就很讨厌被圈养
I used to hate being fenced in.
又凭什么指望  你会心甘情愿地被束缚呢？
So why did I expect you to be any different?
我大概是害怕你太像我了吧
I guess I was afraid you were so much like me.
像你有什么不好的呢？
What's wrong with being like you?
没什么不好的
Nothing.
因为你妈妈最棒了
Because your mom is the best.
而且  她总是能想到办法
And she always has a plan.
这次不行了
Not this time.
他来了
He's here.
准备好做炸鸡块了吗  弗莱？
Are we ready to fry, Fry?
再等五分钟  亲爱的
Five minutes, pumpkin.
四分钟
Make it four. Oh.
它跑哪儿去了？
Where is she?
那群逃跑的鸡自己掉进玉米谷仓里了
Them runaway chickens, uh, have got themselves stuck in a corn silo.
你说的是玉米谷仓吗？
In the silo, you say?
好极了  我去迎接客人
Excellent. I'll go and greet our guest.
三分钟后开始生产鸡块
Production starts in three minutes.
三分钟？
Three?
看来这回你们气数已尽了  小鸡们
Looks like you've just run out of cluck, little chickens.
研磨机  玉米谷仓
这东西底下好像有一台研磨机
I think there's a grinder at the bottom of this thing.
不过从好的一面来看  我们在被磨成碎块之前
On the plus side, though, we will all probably drown
应该就会被玉米渣子淹死了
before we're ground into tiny, wee pieces.
等一下
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
爆米花
Popcorn.
爆米花  大家快看  这些可以做爆米花
Popcorn, everyone. Look. Look, popcorn.
洛奇  我觉得现在不太适合…
Rocky, I don't think this is the time to…
它能解决生活中的所有难题
The answer to all life's problems.
可不是嘛！
Of course.
麦可  我们需要加热玉米
Mac, we need heat.
很热很热
Lots of it. Oh.
这个能行吗？
Will this work?
好极了
Perfect.
谁有火柴？
Now, does anyone have a match?
你真是个彻头彻尾的疯子
Yeah, you and a raving lunatic.
你会把我们都炸成碎片的
You'll blow us all to bits.
而且  最后一根火柴已经用掉了
Besides, we've used the last one.
用光光了哦！
真糟糕
Oh no.
不愧是我的女儿
That's my girl.
我能再次表达  对于个人健康和安全的担忧吗？
Um, can I once again raise my health and safety concerns?
什么担忧？
What is it?
好吧
All right.
味道不错呢
Mm. That tastes nice.
还有吗？
Is there any more?
但你猜怎么着？
But guess what?
就在大爆竹查理  以为我们回到了英国的时候
Just as Whizzbang Charlie thought we were back in Blighty,
敌军在我们的后方开火了
enemy fire at six o'clock.
老天爷啊  这是在下爆米花雨吗？
Ye gods. It's raining popcorn?
可真是经典的英伦天气
Good old British weather.
变幻莫测
Unpredictable.
你永远料不到会发生什么
You never know what's coming.
太不像话了
Outrageous.
-太好啦！  -我们逃出来啦
-Get in there! -We made it.
看呀
Look. Whoo-hoo!
法勒已经帮我们准备好了逃跑路线
Fowler's only gone and set up our escape route.
干得漂亮  老伙计
Well done, you old sausage.
跟我来个坚定的握手就可以了  谢谢
Firm handshake will do, thank you.
任务完成  我们现在快撤吧？
Mission accomplished. Now let's fly this crazy coop, huh?
是的
Oh yes.
快看  尼克
Oh, look, Nick.
回家的路上有零食吃吗？
Have we got snacks for the way home?
好了  走吧
All right. On you go.
金吉  你不过来吗？
Ginger, are you coming?
你们先走吧
No, I'm not.
我要回去
I'm going back.
去救芙瑞祖吗？
For Frizzle?
去救芙瑞祖和其他所有的鸡
For Frizzle and all the chickens.
好！
Yes!
虽然住在与世隔绝的孤岛  但我们不能对世间的苦难袖手旁观
Just because where we live is cut off from the world doesn't mean we are too.
没有鸡能活成一座孤岛
No chicken is an island.
我们支持你  金吉
We are with you, Ginger.
对  我也是
Aye, me too.
还有我
Me four.
老鼠兄弟与你共进退
The rats are in.
好  说说作战计划吧  妈妈
Right. What's the plan, Mum?
噢  我觉得你还是别…
Oh, well, I didn't think you…
洛奇
Rocky.
莫莉  你确定自己准备好战斗了吗？
Hey, Molly, um, are you sure you're ready for this?
打从出生起就准备好了  爸爸
I was hatched ready, Dad.
这孩子确实很像我
She is a lot like me.
弗莱博士
Dr. Fry!
屋顶上的噪音是怎么回事？
What was that noise up on the roof?
听上去像是爆炸声
Sounded like an explosion.
好像有一个谷仓的顶炸了
Looks like one of the silos has blown its top.
也许你不该让那些鸡…
Maybe you shouldn't have put those chickens
进研磨机  亲爱的
through the grinder, my love.
别开玩笑了
Don't be ridiculous.
麦丽莎  准备好了吗？  今天可是我们的大日子
Melisha, all ready for the big day?
当然  雷金纳
Oh yes, Reginald.
一切都准备妥当了
Everything is tickety-boo.
很好  我的卡车也准备就绪了
Jolly good. My truck is ready to go.
我们得赶快行动
We've got to move fast.
特维迪正忙着在外面招呼客人
While Tweedy is busy with her guest outside,
我们趁现在溜回去
we sneak back in.
莫莉  你带邦蒂、芭布丝和麦可  去他们关鸡的地方
Molly, you take Bunty, Babs and Mac to where all the chickens are.
快来
Come on.
这边
This way. Ah.
小心别被看到
Stay out of sight
准备好阻止那些鸡走上楼梯
and get ready to stop the chickens going up that staircase.
洛奇  我们必须掌握那个按钮
Rocky, we've got to get hold of that button.
关闭项圈的功能
And disable those collars.
项圈一旦失效
As soon as the collars are off,
莫莉她们就会带所有的鸡逃离
Molly's team leads the chickens out of there.
我们冲出去
We bust our way out.
开走卡车
Steal the truck,
然后就大功告成了
then we're home free.
好的  那我们还等什么呢？
Well, what are we waiting for?
-好嘞  我们上吧  -是今天就去吗？
-All right. Let's do this. -We're doing it today, are we?
我刚才说到哪儿了？哦  对了
So where was I? Ah, yes.
大爆竹查理的飞机起落架受损
Whizzbang Charlie had lost his undercarriage,
飞机也着火了…
and the old crate was catching fire…
麦丽莎  其实我  为今天这个大日子准备了一个惊喜
Actually, Melisha, I have a little something for our big day.
噢  雷金纳  这也太突然了
Why, Reginald, this is all very sudden.
番茄酱？
Ketchup?
不
Oh. No, no.
是一种全新的酱料
Something completely new.
我称之为“灵魂蘸酱”
I call it "the dip."
它有点甜
It's… sweet.
又有点酸
And sour.
人生不就是如此吗  雷金纳？
Aren't we all, Reginald?
弗莱博士？
Dr. Fry?
我在呢  亲爱的
Yes, my beloved?
快说出那句我渴望已久的话吧
Say those words I am longing to hear.
快干活  白痴
Get on with it, you idiot.
所有鸡
是那只会跳放克舞的鸡  还有那只姜黄色的鸡
It's the funky chicken and the ginger one too.
糟了  我老婆知道了一定会生气的
Oh no, my wife will not be happy with this.
快过来  你们这两只淘气的小鸡！
Come on here now, you naughty little chickens!
天啊
Oh dear.
有缘再会了哦  鸡蛋头  好笑吗？
See you on the flip side, egghead. You get it?
弗莱博士？你在上面磨蹭什么呢？
Dr. Fry? What's going on up there?
快来
Quick. Come on.
弗莱博士！
Dr. Fry! Dr. Fry!
-哈喽？  -弗莱博士！
Hello? -Dr. Fry!
-有人吗？  -弗莱博士！
Anybody there? -Dr. Fry!
弗莱博士！
Dr. Fry!
我的鸡块呢？
Where are my nuggets?
说真的  那男人真是个没脑子的…
Honestly, that man is about as much use as a headless…
鸡！
Chicken!
我们来做鸡块吧
Let's make some nuggets.
糟了
Oh no.
不好  这下糟了  麦可
No. This is not good, Mac.
芙瑞祖  你在哪儿？
Oh, Frizzle. Where are you? Ooh!
轮到我了  再见
My turn. Bye-bye.
芙瑞祖！
Frizzle!
美好的阳光…
Lovely sunshine.
-不  等等  -按住她
-No, wait. -Hold on to her.
♪ We're goin' where the sea is blue ♪
麦可  快点
Mac, hurry.
♪ We've seen it in the movies… ♪
我拿到了
I got it. I got it.
我没拿到！
I don't got it!
洛奇
Rocky.
♪ For me and you ♪
加油  金吉！
Go, Ginger!
♪ 我们都去欢度暑假 ♪
♪ We're all goin' on a summer holiday ♪
♪ 一周两周不用工作 ♪
♪ No more workin' for a week or two… ♪
大家来一起跳舞呀  我们要去度假喽
Come on, everybody. We're goin' on holiday.
不  芭布丝
No, Babs.
他们要把大家都变成鸡块
They're going to turn everyone into nuggets.
♪ For a week or two ♪
♪ 一起去那阳光灿烂的地方 ♪
♪ We're going Where the sun shines brightly… ♪
别跳了  兄弟
Not now, mate.
♪ Where the sea is blue ♪
♪ We've seen it in the movies ♪
拜托  麦可  快点
Please, Mac. Hurry.
快好了
Nearly done.
就差一点点…
Just one more bit of jiggerypokery, and…
发生了什么事？这是什么情况？
What happened? What's goin' on?
芙瑞祖  这里不是什么美好乐园
Frizzle, this isn't the best place ever.
你只有在被切碎
You only get your own bucket
炸熟了以后  才会被装进纸桶
when they've chopped you up and cooked you.
你是专门回来救我的？
And you came back for me?
当然啦
Of course.
姐妹  我们说好了要同甘共苦的呀
It's me and you, kidda. All the way.
该走喽！
Time to go!
试试把他们推回去！
Try to push them back!
太多鸡了！
There's too many! Ooh!
这是度假村的其中一项活动吗？
Is this one of the activities?
妈妈！
Mum!
金吉！
Ginger!
快看  是用来装鸡块的纸桶
Look. There's all the buckets!
那个按钮！
The button!
就这么办
That's it.
芙瑞祖  跳上邦蒂的肩膀
Frizzle, get on Bunty's shoulders.
什么？
What?
相信我
Trust me.
上来吧
Up ya get.
好样的  莫莉
Good goin', Molly.
干得漂亮  莫莉！
Good job, Molly!
莫莉？
Molly?
我自己能行  爸爸  你快去救妈妈
I got this, Dad. Help Mum.
莫莉  小心
Molly, watch out.
瞧瞧这是什么？
What have we here?
小一号的你  妈妈  接住
A little you. Mum, catch.
他们要过去了  妈妈！
They're going over, Mum!
金吉  我们拦不住了！
Ginger, we can't hold them!
来不及了  妈妈  快按吧！
You can't wait, Mum. Do it now!
有时候…
Sometimes…
就得放手一搏呀
you've just got to take a leap.
不！
No!
咯咯咕咕哒！
Cock-a-doodle-doo! Huh?
不！
No! No! No!
金吉！
Ginger!
我抓住你了
I got ya. I got ya.
好吧
Well, now.
你们三个应该够做一大桶鸡块了
I suppose you three might make a bucketful.
再见喽
Bye-bye.
我们又赢了
Again.
危险  鸡体型过大
快来
Come on.
怎么这么久还没好？
Ugh. What's taking so long?
还快餐呢
So much for fast food.
有意思  听起来像是…
That's funny. Sounds like a…
鸡群狂奔！
…stampede!
-快上车  -赶紧的
-Get your skates on. -Move your tail feathers.
-大家快来  -快！
Come on. Come on!
你确定知道这玩意该怎么操作吗？
You sure you know how this works?
知道…
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
这是油门、这是刹车  还有一个多余的踏板？
Go, stop, and a spare one?
快！我们快撤！
Come on! We have to go!
全速前进！
Full speed ahead!
方向错了！
Wrong way!
你挂的哪一档？
What gear are you in?
噢  我穿得很高档吗？
Oh, I call this "smart casual."
喂！
Ah, you there!
你们这养鸡场也太离谱了吧？
What kind of crazy henhouse is this?
麦丽莎？
Melisha?
你为什么打扮成鸡块的样子？
Why are you dressed like a nugget?
出口在那里！
There's the exit!
把她甩下去！
Get her off!
舰桥控制
这个普通纸桶装不下吧
I think they're gonna need a bigger bucket.
我来也！
Chocks away! -Huh?
策应小队的TI法勒前来报到
T.I. Fowler, Getaway Division. Reporting for duty.
没有你我们可怎么办呀  法勒？
Where would we be without you, Fowler?
亲爱的！亲爱的！
Darling! Darling!
Blech. Darling!
处理器严重过热了  现在很危险
The processor is dangerously overheating.
宝贝  小心…
Pumpkin, watch out for the, uh…
-见鬼！  -什么？
Oh blast! What?
我好像把雨伞落在那儿了
I think I left my umbrella in there.
出去度假最开心的环节  就是回家了  不是吗？
Oh! The best thing about going on holiday is getting back home, isn't it?
是呀  可不是嘛  芭布丝？
Yes, it is. Isn't it, Babs?
修好了
Oh! -All fixed.
就是有一颗螺丝松了
Just had a screw loose.
手边常备几个纸桶还真不错  饿了随时都能用得上
Good to have a bucket or two handy in case you're feeling peckish.
有很多爆米花  大家都有份
Plenty for everyone.
这个按钮貌似能让你没头脑地傻乐
This makes you happy and brainless, apparently.
是的  我感觉到了
Oh yeah, I feel it.
好神奇呀
It's amazin'.
伙计  我还没把它打开呢
Mate, I haven't turned it on yet.
似乎我们终于迎来了幸福的结局呢
Well, it looks like we've finally got our happy ending.
还是称之为幸福的开端吧
Ah, let's just call this our happy beginning.
莫莉军士  现在汇报侦察情况
Sergeant Molly, reporting from reconnaissance.
北面田野以外发现养鸡场
Chicken farm, beyond the north field.
一个笼子里关了30只鸡
Thirty birds to a cage.
可怜的孩子们
Poor little kiddas.
好了  各位
Right, everyone.
我一点也不喜欢这样
I don't like this one bit.
是时候行动了
It's go time.
我有一个问题
I've just got one question.
现在又可以打鸣了吗？
Is crowing back on the agenda?
那当然
Oh, definitely.
大家准备好了吗？
Ready, everyone?
-准备好了！  -准备好了！
Ready! -Ready!
咯咯咕咕哒！
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
♪ Let me tell you all about my baby ♪
♪ You will never find her misbehavin' ♪
♪ Oh, she's such a dime ♪
♪ I think I found the brightest star Up in the sky ♪
♪ Just one little look And she'll disarm ya ♪
♪ Everybody tells me she's a charmer ♪
♪ Never gets in trouble She's the apple of my eye ♪
♪ She's so sweet ♪
♪ Like butter wouldn't melt, heavenly ♪
♪ With a little bit of hell I need ♪
♪ To keep her to myself, no need ♪
♪ What would I do? ♪
♪ Do ♪
♪ Without my sweet ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Cherry pie, buttercup Sugar, little honeybee ♪
♪ Never thought That I would love another ♪
♪ Words, they can't describe The way I love her ♪
♪ She fills my cup all the way up ♪
♪ Can't get enough, I know ♪
♪ Sometimes she drives me crazy ♪
♪ I never could get mad at my baby ♪
♪ Don't want her changin' ♪
♪ I just want her by my side ♪
♪ For my whole life ♪
♪ She's the brightest light ♪
♪ In the highest ♪
♪ What would I do? ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Without my sweet baby ♪
♪ Cherry pie, buttercup She's still got the world to see ♪
深切怀念莫瑞斯·摩根